dbschenker.com 2019-05-14

# Privacy Policy

161110_icono_product_teaser Shape Shape 161110_icono_product_teaser icon-arrow-left icon-arrow-right icon-first icon-last 161110_icono_product_teaser 161110_icono_product_teaser location-pin 161110_icono_product_teaser 161110_icono_product_teaser contact-desktop-white careers-desktop-white

* * *

Change country

Change language

  * EN

  *     *   * com.coremedia.blueprint.cae.contentbeans.CMPlaceholderImpl$$[id=282] 

The protection of your personal data is important to you - and for us as well. 

Because of that, we will inform you on this page about which data we collect, why we need this data and how you can contradict the data collection.   

#### 

Schenker AG is the party responsible for collecting and processing your data. The appointed data protection officer is Mr. Maik Goehrke. If you have any questions, suggestions and/or criticism in relation to data protection, please contact: 

 **Schenker AG  
Maik Goehrke  
Kruppstraße 4   
45128 Essen

**

#### 

All data collection and processing is performed for specific purposes. These may result from technical necessities, contractual requirements, or explicit customer requests. For technical reasons, certain data might be collected and stored during a visit to dbschenker.com. As for example the date and duration of the visit, the web pages used, the identification data of the browser and operating system type used, and the website from which you visit us.

If you register for one of our newsletter, the following required information is collected: Salutation, first name, last name, E-Mail address, industry you are working in.  
In this case, we may use your e-mail address for promotional purposes.

If you sign up for our newsletter “logistics NewsFeed”, we save the IP address of the computer system assigned to you by your Internet service provider (ISP) and the date and time of registration. We save this data to track (potential) abuse of the email address of a data subject, for our own legal protection. You can deregister from the newsletter at any time under [unsubscribe "logistics NewsFeed"](http://seu2.cleverreach.com/f/98765-110554/) or by clicking the deregister link at the end of your newsletter.  
If you object to the promotional use of your data, your data will only be used anonymized, for statistical analysis purposes.

To continuously improve our offerings, we save and analyze usage data from the online area on a pseudonymized basis. The legal basis for this is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.

To the extent that we request consent to process your personal data, it serves as the legal basis according to Article 6(1)(a) GDPR.

For processing of personal data required to fulfill a contract with you, the contract is the legal basis according to Article 6(1)(b) GDPR. Article 6(1)(b) GDPR also applies to processing operations that are required to execute preliminary measures, for example, if you ask about our products or services.

If our company is subject to legal demands that require us to process personal data, for example, to fulfill tax responsibilities, then processing is based on Article 6(1)(c) GDPR.

If you click on a link to an external page, you will move outside the pages of dbschenker.com. Schenker AG is therefore not responsible for the content, services or products offered on the linked website and also for the privacy and technical safety on the linked website.

#### 

Your data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer required for the purpose for which they were collected (e.g. within the framework of a contractual relationship). Your data must also be deleted if it is not permissible to store them (particularly if the data are inaccurate and correction is not possible). Where legal or practical obstacles prevent deletion, the data are blocked (e.g. special archiving obligations).

#### 

The transmission of data and emails via the internet is generally unencrypted, and is therefore unprotected against third-party access. When you contact us by email, the confidentiality of the information provided cannot be guaranteed during the transmission; we therefore recommend that confidential information should be sent exclusively by letter.

#### 

  * You can request information about what data is stored about you.
  * You may request rectification, deletion and limitation of the processing (blocking) of your personal data as long as this is legally permissible and possible within the framework of an existing contractual relationship
  * You have the right to appeal to a supervisory authority. The supervisory authority responsible for the Schenker AG is: Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz Nordrhein-Westfalen Kavalleriestrasse 2-4, 402013 Duesseldorf   
  * You have the right to transfer the data that you have provided us on the basis of a consent or a contract (data portability).
  * If you have given us consent for data processing, you can revoke it at any time in the same way that you have granted it. The revocation of the consent does not affect the legality of the processing due to the consent until the revocation.
  * To exercise your rights, send an email to: [dataprotection@dbschenker.com](mailto:dataprotection@dbschenker.com)

#### 

For the execution of the contract, the activation of instructions-dependent processors is usually a must, such as data center operators, printing or shipping service providers or other parties involved in the performance of the contract.

External service providers, who process data for us, are carefully selected by us and are strictly contractually obligated. The service providers work according to our instructions, which is ensured by strict contractual regulations, by technical and organisational measures and by supplementary controls.

Furthermore, your data will only be transmitted if you have given us your express consent or because of a legal regulation.

Transmission to third countries outside the EU/EEA or to an international organisation shall not take place unless there are adequate guarantees. These include the EU standard contractual clauses and an adequacy decision of the European Commission.

#### 

We want to give you the opportunity to make an informed decision for or against the use of cookies, unless these are not strictly necessary for the technical functioning of the website. 

Cookies are small text files in which personal data can be saved. Our data protection notice is intended to ensure that you are fully aware of data collection and processing, even where our web pages use cookies, and that you can make a correspondingly informed decision.

We therefore inform you here about the type and scope of the intended use of cookies on our web pages. The use of dbschenker.com/global is generally possible without cookies, unless these do not serve for technical purposes.

You can prevent tracking by cookies by changing your browser settings or prevent third-party cookies from being saved. You can change your browser settings as follows: 

We also recommend regularly checking and deleting the cookies that are saved, where they are not specifically desired. 

We use cookies that are active from the start of your visit to our website until the end of the respective browser session. These cookies are automatically invalid and deleted as soon as you close your internet browser. These cookies are also known as "session cookies". Session cookies are used in the following areas:

  * The cookie identifies the user when visiting the website for the duration of the active session.
  * The cookie ensures that once the language has been selected, it is retained and applied for the duration of the active session, and continues to be provided to the user when they change between pages.
  * The cookie serves for data security, and prevents data and content from being manipulated, accessed, and transmitted to other systems by third parties.​​​​​​​

Name

| 

Function

| 

Storage time  
  
---|---|---  
  
_pk_ses.15.dd94

| 

Saves user session information 

| 

as long as the session is active, max 10 hours   
  
_pk_id.15.dd94

| 

Identifys user and tracks analytics data (anonymized)

| 

13 months  
  
_ga| Used to distinguish users| 2 years  
_gid| Used to distinguish users| 24 hours  
_gat| Used to throttle request rate| 60 seconds  
  
_ss

| 

This cookie stores the session id for your web visit. It is used by SharpSpring to group together web visits from a single visitor served a SharpSpring token (ss_tk).

| 

30 hours  
  
_ss_tk

| This is the SharpSpring first-party cookie. We use it in conjunction with our marketing automation platform to ensure that web visitors receive the information that most interests them| 25 years  
_ss_referrer| This is a traffic referrer cookie. We store the visitor’s referrer location for use by our marketing automation platform| 6 hours  
koitk| Session Ids from. Shaprspring| 1 month  
sid| Session Ids from. Shaprspring| 1 week  
DSID| Google advertising cookie used for user tracking and ad targeting purposes| Session  
IDE| 

These cookies are created by Google DoubleClick and are used to show personalized advertisements (ads) based on previous visits to our website.

| 18 month  
fr| Encrypted Facebook ID and Browser ID| 3 months  
wd| Facebook cookie to improve performance (display size)| 7 days  
reg_fb_gate| URL of last first Faceook page| Session  
reg_fb_ref| URL of last visited Faceook page| Session  
reg_ext_refU| Facebook cookie (if) URL of external referral website| Session  
datr| Facebook cookie Browser identification and timestamp| 2 years  
dpr| Facebook cookie|   
pl| 

Facebook cookie Yes/No

| 90 days  
presence| Facebook cookie Chat state| Session  
sb| 

Facebook cookie Browser identification and timestamp

spin Session Facebook cookie

| 

2 years  
  
xs| Facebook cookie Session ID| 90 days  
L1c| 

Browser ID cookie

| Current Session  
BizoID| LinkedIn Ad analytics| 

6 months  
  
BizoData| LinkedIn Ad analytics| 

6 months  
  
BizoUserMatchHistory| LinkedIn Ad analytics| 6 months  
BizoNetwork

PartnerIndex

| LinkedIn Ad analytics| 6 months  
_guid| Eloqua tracking|   
_lipt| Eloqua tracking|   
bcookie| LinkedIn Browser ID cookie| 1 year  
jobs_hru| LinkedIn Browser ID cookie|   
lang| LinkedIn Browser ID cookie|   
li_oatml| LinkedIn Browser ID cookie|   
liap| LinkedIn Browser ID cookie|   
lidc| LinkedIn routing cookie| 1 day  
org_tcphc| LinkedIn routing cookie|   
sdsc| LinkedIn routing cookie|   
  
spectroscopyI

| LinkedIn routing cookie|   
1P_JAR| Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.| 1 day  
OGPC| Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.| 60 days  
NID| 

Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.

| 6 month  
SSID| Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.| 2 years  
SAPSID| Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.| 2 years  
APISID| Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.| 2 years  
HSID| Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.| 2 years  
SIDCC| Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.| 2 years  
DSID| Google cookie. These cookies are used to collect website statistics and track conversion rates.| 2 years  
UET| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
MUID| 

cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad

| 13 months  
NAP| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
PPLState| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
SRCHD| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
SRCHUID| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
SRCHUSR| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
WLID| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
WLS| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
_EDGE_S| 

cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad

| 13 months  
_SS| cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad| 13 months  
_U| 

cookie that tracks interaction on website after someone has clicked on a bing ad

| 13 months  
  
#### 

Insofar as you have given your consent, this website uses Google Analytics and Google Ads, a web analytics services provided by Google LLC. This makes it possible to assign data, sessions and interactions across multiple devices to a pseudonymous user ID, thus analyzing the activities of a user across devices.

Google Analytics uses so-called cookies, these are text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, in the event of activation of IP anonymisation on this website, your IP address will be shortened beforehand by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. We point out that on this website Google Analytics has been extended by an IP anonymization to ensure an anonymous collection of IP addresses (so-called IP masking). The IP address provided by Google Analytics as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. For more information about Terms of Use and Privacy, please visit [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and also [Google Privacy&Terms](https://policies.google.com/?hl=en). 

On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage to the website operator. Advertisements are based on your interest in products previously shown to you on other websites. For this purpose, cookies are stored on your computer that contain your IP address and usage data.

The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 Sec. 1 sentence 1 lit. a GDPR. The recipient of the data collected is Google.

The personal data will be transmitted under the EU-US Privacy Shield on the basis of the adequacy decision of the European Commission in the USA. You can get the certificate here: [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI) 

The data sent by us and linked to cookies, user IDs (eg user ID) or advertising IDs will be automatically deleted after 14 months. The deletion of data whose retention period has been reached is done automatically once a month. You can revoke your consent at any time with future effect by preventing the storage of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible.

You may also prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google. Download and install Google [Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en) 

Opt-out cookies prevent future collection of your data when you visit this website. To prevent Universal Analytics tracking across devices, you must opt-out on all systems you use. If you click here, the opt-out cookie for this website will be set:

​​​​​​​  

#### 

We use the Matomo analysis service on our website. Small text files (cookies) store data about how you use our website, including your IP address. These data are anonymized and stored by us. If you do not wish to agree to the analysis of your use of our website, you can change your browser settings at any time to prevent cookies from being used. In this case, however, it may be the case that not all functions can be used.  

#### 

Insofar as you have given your consent, this website uses Sharpspring, a web analytics service provided by SharpSpring.). This makes it possible to analyze the behavior of individuals on our websites in the context of advertising.

### Loged Data

Insofar as you have given your consent we automatically collect and store, certain information about the your device (computer, tablet, smartphone) and the user’s activities. This includes:

  * Preferences and settings: time zone, language, and character size.
  * Identifiers: IP address.
  * Technical information: type of device, operating system name and version, device manufacturer, browser information (type, version), screen resolution.
  * Coarse geographic information: geographic location derived from the IP address.

We collect this data for the proper operation of our Platform. Until the user becomes a “lead” this data cannot be linked to a specific individual.

### Traffic Data

Data generated by the use of the Platform also include:

  * Information about use of the Platform: date stamp, URL of the visited page, URL of the last webpage visited before visiting our Platform or a website using our Platform. URL of the last webpage visited before visiting our Service.

  * History of interaction with our webpages: pages viewed, time spent on a page, click through, clickstream data; queries made, search history, search results selected; comments made, type of service requested, purchases made.

We collect this data to understand how our Platform is used and to create statistics on the use of our Platform. Until the user becomes a “lead” this data cannot be linked to a specific individual.

### Lead Data

If a visitor interacts with us, for example, to inquire about a service or registering on the platform, the visitor becomes a lead. In these cases, we will collect information provided to us through the form or questionnaire used to make the request, or the contact or other information provided at a trade show or industry event. The information is provided directly and voluntarily by the individual. Depending on the circumstances, the information may include:

  * First and Last Name

  * Name of the business

  * Email address

  * Street address, city, state, province and/or country

  * Telephone number

  * Website URL

  * Social Media Handles

  * Mobile Number

We collect to respond to a request from a lead so that we may provide information about our Service.

#### 

**1) The party responsible for processing of personal data**

Schenker AG is the party responsible for the processing of your data. The appointed data protection officer is Mr. Maik Goehrke. If you have any questions, suggestions and/or criticism in relation to data protection, please contact: 

Schenker AG  
Maik Goehrke  
Kruppstraße 4   
45128 Essen

 **2) Which data do we collect  and why do we process the data?**

Fan pages on Social Media   
You can find us in various social media with their own appearance. In this way, we would like to provide you with a broad, multimedia offer and exchange ideas with you on important topics for you. In addition to the respective provider of a social network, we also collect and process personal user data on fan pages. This notice also informs you of what information we collect from you on our social media appearances, how we use them, and how you may object to our use of the data. The respective data processing purposes and data categories can be found in the respective offer, which is detailed below. The activities carried out by us and described in more detail below in social media are based on a balance of interests pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

 **A) Facebook**

On the [DB Schenker Group channel,](https://www.facebook.com/DB-Schenker-497409020719760/) we present our company on Facebook. If you visit our fan page, Facebook Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, D2 Dublin, Ireland collects, stores and processes your personal information in accordance with its privacy policy. The privacy policy can be found [here](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). 

In addition, processing of personal data by us takes place only to a very limited extent.   
For the purpose of the needs-oriented design and continuous optimization of our pages, we use the statistics service Facebook Insights. This service records your activity on our site and makes it available to us in anonymised statistics. This gives us insights amongst others on the activity of our fan page visitors, the clicks of our page, the range of posts, clicks and average duration of video playback, information from which countries and cities our visitors come from, as well as statistics on the gender relations of our visitors.

Conclusions on individual users and access to individual user profiles by the administrator are not possible.

More information about Facebook Insights can be found [here](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/information_about_page_insights_data).

Regarding the processing of Insights data, there is a shared responsibility between Facebook and us. Details are provided in the Joint Controller Addendum, which you can find [here](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page_controller_addendum).

Facebook Ireland provides the essence of the page insights supplement to affected persons.  
In addition, we store usernames and comments that are deleted for violating the netiquette. These will only be tracked if necessary for proof of legal disputes within the limitation period.  
In addition, we do not store and process personal data about you, with the exception of an online competition. In an online competition, the winners will be publicly marked with their username and asked to contact each other within 14 days via email. The winners must send their name and address so that the prize can be sent. These data are processed by us exclusively for the purpose of processing the online competition. For the online competition the respective terms of conditions of participation apply. The e-mails with the addresses are always deleted after 30 days, as long as they are not needed beyond that for the winning notification.

 **B) Instagram**

The most beautiful pictures from the media library are posted on the [DB Schenker channel](https://www.instagram.com/dbschenkerglobal/), showing users the work of the various business units. The focus is on ecology and sustainability, innovation and technology as well as strengthening the employer brand, with a focus on all business areas. Likewise cross-media contents are published.

If you visit our fan page, personal data will be stored and processed by Instagram, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, D2 Dublin, Ireland as an Instagram provider in accordance with Instagram's Privacy Policy. The privacy policy can be found [here](https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875).  
In addition, processing of personal data by us takes place only to a very limited extent. 

For the purpose of the needs-oriented design and continuous optimization of our pages, we use the statistics service Instagram Insights. This service records your activity on our site and makes it available to us in anonymised statistics. This gives us insights about the interactions of our fan page visitors, the clicks of our page, the reach of posts, information about our followers' activity, as well as information from which countries and cities our visitors come from, as well as statistics on the gender relations of our visitors. Conclusions on individual users and access to individual user profiles by the administrator are not possible.

In addition, we store usernames and comments that are deleted for violating the netiquette. These will only be tracked if necessary for proof of legal disputes within the limitation period.  
In addition, we do not store and process personal data about you, with the exception of an online competition and Fan posts. In an online competition, the winners will be publicly marked with their username and asked to contact each other within 14 days via E-Mail. The winners must send their name and address so that the prize can be sent. These data are processed by us exclusively for the purpose of processing the online competitions. For online competitions the respective terms of conditions of participation apply. The e-mails with the addresses are always deleted after 30 days, as long as they are not needed beyond that for the winning notification.

We ask users, after we have publicly and without obligation, asked for permission to repost their pictures on the Instagram channel [DB Schenker](https://www.instagram.com/dbschenkerglobal/). The declaration of consent will be saved by us as a screenshot and the image as a file with details of the user. The photos and consent form will be stored as long as the photo is posted on the channel or until the consent is revoked. The reposted photo is being stored on the Instagram server for technical reasons [Facebook Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbor, D2 Dublin, Ireland]. A revocation is possible at any time (see below for details). In the case of cancellation, the image and the user's details are deleted immediately.

 **C) Twitter**

The Twitter channel [@DBSchenker](https://twitter.com/DBSchenker) is used for events, press and public relations on all topics of our company.  
If you visit our Channel, which stores and processes Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA, as the operator of Twitter personal information, to the extent described in the Privacy Policy. 

The privacy policy can be found [here](https://twitter.com/de/privacy).

In addition, we do not store and process personally identifiable information about you. Just in case you send us a direct message, the user name will be saved.

In addition, we store usernames and comments that are deleted for violating the netiquette. These will only be tracked if necessary for proof of legal disputes within the limitation period.

 **3) Are data disclosed to third parties?**

For the provision of our offer usually the involvement of instruction-dependent processors is required, such as data center operators, printing or shipping service providers or other parties.   
External service providers who process data for us on behalf of us are carefully selected by us and contractually strictly committed. The service providers work according to our instructions, which is ensured by strict contractual arrangements, by technical and organizational measures and by additional controls.  
Moreover, your data will only be transmitted if you have given us an express consent or as a result of statutory provisions.  
We point out that when processing through Facebook, Instagram and Twitter data of users may be processed outside the territory of the European Union. This may result in risks for the users because e.g. enforcement of user rights could be made more difficult. For details, please refer to the privacy policy of Facebook, Instagram and Twitter. With respect to US providers certified under the Privacy Shield, we point out that they are committed to upholding the EU's privacy standards.  
We do not transfer data to third countries outside the EU / EEA or to an international organization unless there are adequate safeguards. These include the EU standard contractual clauses and an adequacy decision by the European Commission.

 **4) When will your data be deleted?**

If we have collected personal data from you, we only store it for as long as it is necessary for the fulfillment of the purpose for which it was collected (eg in the context of a contractual relationship) or if this is provided for by law. Thus, we save your data in the framework of a contractual relationship at least until the complete termination of the contract. Subsequently, the data will be kept for the duration of the statutory retention period.

 **5) What rights do users have?**

  * You can request information about what data is stored about you.
  * You may request rectification, deletion and limitation of the processing (blocking) of your personal data as long as this is legally permissible and possible within the framework of an existing contractual relationship
  * You have the right to appeal to a supervisory authority. The supervisory authority responsible for the Schenker AG is: Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz Nordrhein-Westfalen Kavalleriestrasse 2-4, 402013 Duesseldorf 
  * poststelle@ldi.nrw.de
  * You have the right to transfer the data that you have provided us on the basis of a consent or a contract (data portability).
  * If you have given us consent for data processing, you can revoke it at any time in the same way that you have granted it. The revocation of the consent does not affect the legality of the processing due to the consent until the revocation.
  * You may object to the processing of data for reasons that arise from your particular situation, if the processing of data is based on our legitimate interests.
  * You can contradict the advertising approach at any time with effect for the future (advertising contradiction).

To exercise your rights, send an email to: [dataprotection@dbschenker.com](mailto:dataprotection@dbschenker.com)

With regard to data processing on social networks, we recommend that you respond to requests such as : for information or other questions about user rights, to apply directly to the respective social network for a cancellation request, since only Facebook, Instagram, Twitter have full access to your user data. If you no longer wish to use the data processing described here in the future, by using the functions "I do not like this page anymore" and / or "Unsubscribe from this page" you can unblock your user profile from our site.

With regard to the processing of personal data via the service "Insights" offered by Facebook, Facebook has assumed the primary responsibility. This concerns the processing of Insights data and the implementation of the data subject rights. Therefore, please contact Facebook directly regarding all obligations under the GDPR with regard to the processing of Insights data. We will forward your inquiries to us on Facebook.

 **6) New functions, updating of the Privacy Policy**

We adapt the privacy policy to changed functionalities or changed legal situations. Therefore, we recommend that you read the privacy policy at regular intervals. If your consent is required or parts of the privacy policy contain provisions of the contractual relationship with you, the changes will only be made with your consent.

Updated: 20.12.2018

#### New functions, updating the privacy policy  

We adapt the privacy policy to changed functionalities. Therefore, we recommend that to read the privacy policy when you visit the new version of dbschenker.com/global

Updated: October 11th, 2018

#####  Your browser version is not supported. Our website might look wrong or appear differently than it should.
